For a bunch of funny friends trying to break into show
business... it's a jungle out there!
Cats Don't Dance is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Mark Dindal.
An ambitious singing and dancing cat in 1939 Hollywood overcomes several
obstacles to fulfill his dream of becoming a movie star.
Danny (voice), played by Scott Bakula.
Sawyer (voice), played by Jasmine Guy.
Sawyer (singing voice), played by Natalie Cole.
Darla Dimple (voice), played by Ashley Peldon.
Darla Dimple (singing voice), played by Lindsay Ridgeway.
Farley Wink (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Cats Don't Dance is a 1997 American animated musical
comedy film directed by Mark Dindal.
The film features the voices of Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Matthew Herried, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, Don
Knotts, Hal Holbrook, Betty Lou Gerson (in her final film role), René Auberjonois, Mark Dindal, and George Kennedy.
In 1993, Cats Don't Dance originated as a proposed film
collaboration between Michael Jackson and David Kirschner.
It was announced as a live-action/animated film project with Jackson
attached to star, and consult on the music and choreography.
However, by 1994, Jackson dropped out of the project.
The project was reverted to Turner Feature Animation, and reconceived into a
fully animated film that homaged classic Hollywood musical films.
Mark Dindal was hired as the director.
The film's musical numbers were written by Randy Newman.
Gene Kelly consulted with the animators on the
choreography before his death in 1996.
The film was Kelly's final film project and is dedicated to his memory.
In 1996, Turner Broadcasting System was merged with Time Warner, and as a result, Cats Don't
Dance was the only fully animated feature produced by Turner Feature Animation.
Cats Don't Dance was released in the United States and
Canada on March 26, 1997, by Warner Bros.
under its Family Entertainment label.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
However, it was a box-office failure, grossing $3.5
million in the United States and Canada.
The film's producer David Kirschner blamed Warner Bros.
for a failed marketing campaign and lack of promotional tie-ins.
Cats Don't Dance won two Annie Awards, one for Best Animated Feature
and the other for Best Music in a Feature Production.
It was the first non-Disney animated film to win in either category.
The film explores themes of dance, villain,
musical, anthropomorphism, hollywood.
The tone is lighthearted.